{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Mohammed Ali","incorrectAnswers":["Bob Dylan","Woody Allen","Prince"],"question":"Who was born with the name Cassius Clay?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A swarm","incorrectAnswers":["A kindle","A pride","A watch"],"question":"What is the word for a group of flies?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Bird's Nest","incorrectAnswers":["The Bamboo Grove","The Panda's Den","The Ancestor's Grave"],"question":"Built for the 2008 Olympics, what is the name of the Beijing city structure that won architecture's Lubetkin Prize?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Japan","incorrectAnswers":["India","Ecuador","Myanmar"],"question":"Which country has a flag of a red circle on a white background?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Redbud","incorrectAnswers":["Magnolia","Mimosa","Oak"],"question":"What is the common name for cercis canadensis, the state tree of Oklahoma?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Churches","incorrectAnswers":["The skin","Winged insects","Soil"],"question":"What is Ecclesiology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Michael Fassbender","incorrectAnswers":["Gerard Butler","Jim Carrey","Robert Redford"],"question":"Which actor has appeared in films including X-Men: Days of Future Past and Inglourious Basterds?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A human soldier is sent from 2029 to 1984 to stop an almost indestructible cyborg killing machine.","incorrectAnswers":["A Marine observes the effects of war on his fellow recruits from their boot camp training to fighting in a war.","The lives of mob hitmen, a boxer, a gangster and his wife, and a pair of bandits intertwine in four tales.","Historical events unfold from the perspective of an Alabama man with an IQ of 75."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie The Terminator?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Pride and Prejudice","incorrectAnswers":["The Fault in Our Stars","Ship of Fools","War and Peace"],"question":"In which book does 'Mr William Collins' appear?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Internet Protocol","incorrectAnswers":["Information Protocol","Internet Program","Internet Portal"],"question":"In computer networking, what is meaning of the initials IP?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest","incorrectAnswers":["Misery","The Birds","M"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Randle Patrick McMurphy'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Bavette","incorrectAnswers":["Farfalle","Tortellini","Conchiglie"],"question":"Which pasta's name means 'Bibs'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Baseball","incorrectAnswers":["Football","Basketball","Ice Hockey"],"question":"This sport is called the \"American pastime\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"One-armed bandit","incorrectAnswers":["Roly Polies","Kachings","Spinning banks"],"question":"Which of these terms is often used to refer to slot machines?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Xenophobia","incorrectAnswers":["Acrophobia","Claustrophobia","Arachnophobia"],"question":"What word refers to the fear of people from other cultures?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Lolita","incorrectAnswers":["Les Liaisons dangereuses","And Then There Were None","Ulysses"],"question":"In which book does 'Humbert Humbert' appear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Epilepsy","incorrectAnswers":["Anemia","Heart Attack","Paralysis"],"question":"In the early 20th century, rattlesnake venom was used to treat which illness?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Ben Affleck","incorrectAnswers":["Keanu Reeves","Donald Sutherland","Christian Bale"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice and Argo?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Ballet","incorrectAnswers":["Tap","Jazz","Hip Hop"],"question":"In which type of dance are there five basic foot positions?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Louis XIV","incorrectAnswers":["Henri III","Charles the Bald","Napoleon Bonaparte"],"question":"Which King of France was known as The Sun King?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Will Truman","incorrectAnswers":["Jack McFarland","Will Buckland","Mark Wilson"],"question":"What is the name of the character played by Eric McCormack on the show 'Will & Grace'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Green Day","incorrectAnswers":["Animal Collective","Fall Out Boy","Blink-182"],"question":"Which band released the classic punk rock album 'American Idiot'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Robert E.Lee","incorrectAnswers":["Ulysses S Grant","George Armstrong Custer","William Tecumseh Sherman"],"question":"Who Commanded The Confederate Armies During The American Civil War?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["Yellow","Blue","Green"],"question":"What color is carmine?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A covey","incorrectAnswers":["A colony","A herd","A field"],"question":"What is the word for a group of partridges?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"It is used as oscillators in radios, watches.","incorrectAnswers":["It is used as an ingredient in the production of glass, bricks, and ceramics.","It is used to relieve pain.","It is used to manufacture dry wall."],"question":"What is the chemical silicon dioxide often used for?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Polio","incorrectAnswers":["Syphilis","Mumps","Smallpox"],"question":"As what is infantile paralysis more commonly known?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1999","incorrectAnswers":["1993","1996","2002"],"question":"In which year was Fight Club released?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Nsafufuo","incorrectAnswers":["Rakı","Bourbon","Sangria"],"question":"Which of these is a popular drink in Ghana?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Uriah Heep"],"question":"Which English rock band released the studio album 'Rubber Soul'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Cambodia","incorrectAnswers":["Ethiopia","Cuba","Indonesia"],"question":"What country was ruled by Pol Pot, leader of the Khmer Rouge party?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Amman","incorrectAnswers":["Tallinn","Accra","Thimphu"],"question":"What is the capital city of Jordan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Parmesan","incorrectAnswers":["Feta","Gouda","Brie"],"question":"What type of cheese would you be most likely to find in a Risotto?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Rabies","incorrectAnswers":["Smallpox","Coronavirus","Diabetes"],"question":"For What Illness Did Louis Pasteur Develop A Cure?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Seattle Mariners","incorrectAnswers":["Seattle Flyers","Seattle Sabres","Seattle Real"],"question":"Which of these is a baseball team based in Seattle?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Holy Grail","incorrectAnswers":["Sacred Grail","Holy Chalice","Sacred Chalice"],"question":"What is the holy cup of Christ called?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Susan Sarandon","incorrectAnswers":["Elisabeth Shue","Sharon Stone","Meryl Streep"],"question":"Who won the 1995 Academy Award for Best Leading Actress for playing the role of Sister Helen Prejean in Dead Man Walking?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Macho","incorrectAnswers":["A Buck","A Boar","A Hob"],"question":"What is the word for a male llama?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Sticky Fingers","incorrectAnswers":["Brown Sugar","The Velvet Underground","Let It Bleed"],"question":"Which Album Cover Did Andy Warhol Design For The Rolling Stones?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Seismologist","incorrectAnswers":["Geologist","Barologist","Gerologist"],"question":"What Do You Call A Person Who Studies Earthquakes?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queen","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Feeder"],"question":"Which British rock band released the song 'You're My Best Friend'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Incredibles","incorrectAnswers":["Toy Story","Finding Nemo","Cars"],"question":"Which animated movie gave us the quote \"Dynaguy, snagged on takeoff! Splashdown, sucked into a vortex... no capes!\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Muhammad Ali","incorrectAnswers":["Michael Jordan","Tiger Woods","Kobe Bryant"],"question":"What sports icon did Will Smith portray to receive an Oscar nomination in 2002?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Papa Doc","incorrectAnswers":["Big Daddy","Pa Lordy","Man Man Judge"],"question":"What was the nickname of President Duvalier of Haiti, who died in 1971?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Scotland","incorrectAnswers":["USA","Russia","New Zealand"],"question":"In which country would you find the city of Edinburgh?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Meredith Brooks","incorrectAnswers":["Quiet Riot","Divinyls","Bow Wow Wow"],"question":"'Bitch' was a one hit wonder in 1997 by which artist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Seth MacFarlane","incorrectAnswers":["Trey Parker","Matt Groening","Will Ferrell"],"question":"Who created the TV show 'Family Guy'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Ancient One","incorrectAnswers":["Agent Peggy Carter","Rocket Raccoon","Valkyrie"],"question":"Tilda Swinton plays the role of which character in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Religion","incorrectAnswers":["Trees","Children","Blood"],"question":"What is Theology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["Yellow","Ten","Eight"],"question":"What does the word 'rosso' mean in Italian?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Clavicle","incorrectAnswers":["Femur","Ulna","Humerus"],"question":"What is the medical name for the collarbone?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Aztecs","incorrectAnswers":["The Incas","The Mayans","The Moche"],"question":"Which empire of 30 million people was crushed by Cortez and his few hundred men in 1521?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Five","incorrectAnswers":["Eight","Seven","Six"],"question":"What does the word 'cinco' mean in Spanish?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tallinn","incorrectAnswers":["Maseru","Belmopan","Dili"],"question":"What is the capital city of Estonia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Gustave Flaubert","incorrectAnswers":["Anatole France","Guy de Maupassant","Charles Perrault"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Madame Bovary'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Lahore","incorrectAnswers":["Lviv","Bishkek","Baku"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Pakistan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Robert De Niro","incorrectAnswers":["Fred Astaire","Jeff Bridges","Michael V. Gazzo"],"question":"Who won the 1974 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actor for playing the role of Vito Corleone in The Godfather Part II?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Interactions among organisms and the water cycle","incorrectAnswers":["Lakes","The structure of cells","Evolution"],"question":"What is ecohydrology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Depeche Mode","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Dead or Alive","Radiohead"],"question":"Which English band released the album 'Music for the Masses'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Monterrey","incorrectAnswers":["Recife","Guatemala City","Bogotá"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Mexico?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"All About Eve","incorrectAnswers":["Trainspotting","Chinatown","Grave of the Fireflies"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A secretly ruthless woman insinuates herself into the lives of an aging actor and her circle of theater friends.'","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Montenegro","incorrectAnswers":["Lebanon","Romania","Bulgaria"],"question":"Podgorica is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Michael Palin","incorrectAnswers":["John Cleese","Terry Gilliam","Eric Idle"],"question":"Which member of the Monty Python comedy team has travelled extensively, making programmes such as 'Pole to Pole' and 'Around the World in 80 Days'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Azuro","incorrectAnswers":["Blau","Azul","Sei"],"question":"What is the Italian word for 'blue'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Zimbabwe","incorrectAnswers":["Zambia","The Netherlands","Western Sahara"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.zw' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"a branch of geology that studies sediments","incorrectAnswers":["bones","the study and treatment of diseases of the urogenital tract","the eyes"],"question":"What is Sedimentology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Arthur Conan Doyle","incorrectAnswers":["Agatha Christie","Oscar Wilde","George Orwell"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Return of Sherlock Holmes'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Choux ","incorrectAnswers":["Filo","Shortcrust","Puff"],"question":"What type of pastry is used for profiteroles?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Rolls-Royce","incorrectAnswers":["Bentley","Mercedes-Benz","Lamborghini"],"question":"Which luxury car brand manufactured a convertible 2013 Phantom model that can fetch over $470,000?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Dallas","incorrectAnswers":["Atlanta","Austin","Houston"],"question":"In which city was President Kennedy killed?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Jackson 5","incorrectAnswers":["Poison","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American pop music family group released the song 'I Want You Back'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Russia","incorrectAnswers":["Bulgaria","Lithuania","Latvia"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Ukraine?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A shoal","incorrectAnswers":["A host","A murder","A kindle"],"question":"What is the word for a group of herrings?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Saul Bellow","incorrectAnswers":["Philip Roth","John Cheever","Flannery O'Connor"],"question":"Who is the author of the books 'Mr. Sammler's Planet' and 'Herzog'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Tallow","incorrectAnswers":["Millow","Bellow","Rellow"],"question":"What is the term for rendered fat that is used in making soap or candles?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Dromedary","incorrectAnswers":["Bactrian","Arabian","Manchurian"],"question":"A one-humped camel is called a _________.","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A Fistful of Dollars","incorrectAnswers":["The Good, the Bad and the Ugly","Hang 'Em High","High Plains Drifter"],"question":"What is the name of the 1964 Spaghetti Western Clint Eastwood starred in, the first of an iconic trilogy?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"60","incorrectAnswers":["12","20","30"],"question":"What is the lowest common multiple of 3, 4 and 5?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Georges Pompidou","incorrectAnswers":["Jaques Chirac","François Mitterrand","Gaston Doumergue"],"question":"Who became President of France after Charles de Gaulle?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Rolling Stones","incorrectAnswers":["McFly","Delirious?","Depeche Mode"],"question":"Which English rock band released the studio album 'Goats Head Soup'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Henry VI","incorrectAnswers":["Richard III","Othello","Macbeth"],"question":"What was Shakespeare's first play?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Cuba","incorrectAnswers":["Puerto Rico","Mexico","The Bahamas"],"question":"Spain ceded Florida to Britain in exchange for this territory.","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Rami Malek","incorrectAnswers":["Christian Bale","Bradley Cooper","Willem Dafoe"],"question":"Who won the 2018 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of Freddie Mercury in Bohemian Rhapsody?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"A kiln","incorrectAnswers":["An inferno","A furnace","A forge"],"question":"What is the name of the type of oven used to make pottery?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Doe","incorrectAnswers":["A Gander","A Jill","A Hen"],"question":"What would you call a female antelope?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Sound and the Fury","incorrectAnswers":["Blood Meridian","In Our Time","The End of the Affair"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Quentin Compson'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Horse and Carriage","incorrectAnswers":["Steam Engine Train","Airplane","Bicycle"],"question":"What was the main form of transportation used during the 17th century?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Pride and Prejudice","incorrectAnswers":["The Fault in Our Stars","Ship of Fools","War and Peace"],"question":"In which book does 'Lydia Bennet' appear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Doors","incorrectAnswers":["Styx","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American rock band released the song 'Alabama Song'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Cricket","incorrectAnswers":["Rugby","Tennis","Bowling"],"question":"The Duckworth Lewis Method Is Used To Keep The Score In Which Sport?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Peter Lorre","incorrectAnswers":["Johnny Depp","John Cusack","Robert De Niro"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Hans Beckert in M?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Euro","incorrectAnswers":["Peso","Lira","Dollar"],"question":"What is the basic unit of currency for San Marino?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"The w in 'walk'","incorrectAnswers":["The m in 'mother'","The b in 'boat'","The k in 'sock'"],"question":"In phonetics, which of these is an example of an approximant sound?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ireland","incorrectAnswers":["Great Britain","New Zealand","Japan"],"question":"The Dingle Peninsula is the westernmost point of which island?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Yellow","incorrectAnswers":["White","Black","Orange"],"question":"Which of these colors is included on the flag of Guinea?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Sheep","incorrectAnswers":["Cow","Moose","Pig"],"question":"Greek Feta cheese is made from the milk of which animal?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Motley Crue","incorrectAnswers":["Metallica","Aerosmith","Def Leppard"],"question":"Which Group Features Tommy Lee As Drummer?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Cob","incorrectAnswers":["A Hob","A Tiercel","A Macho"],"question":"What would you call a male swan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Acht","incorrectAnswers":["Ocho","Otto","Groen"],"question":"In Dutch, what is the word for for 'eight'?","difficulty":"hard"},